We all know driving can be stressful.
我们都知道开车是件很有压力的事。
One minute you’re minding your own business and the next someone cuts you up.
前一秒你还在正常行驶，下一秒就有人突然强行加塞。
Manoeuvres like that can be annoying and irritating, but for some of us, it can make us incandescent with rage.
这样的驾驶操作着实令人心烦气恼，对有些人来说，甚至会让他们怒火中烧。
So what is road rage, and what things can cause it?
那么，什么是路怒症？又有哪些因素会引发路怒症呢？
Road rage, simply put, is a sudden burst of anger that motorists experience when they feel angered by something another driver, cyclist or pedestrian has done.
简单来说，路怒症是驾驶人因受到其他司机、骑行者或行人的行为刺激，而产生的突发性暴怒情绪。
Road rage can manifest itself in several ways, including verbal or physical threats, insults, and even dangerous driving.
路怒症的表现形式多种多样，包括言语或肢体威胁、辱骂，甚至是危险驾驶行为。
The drivers themselves may feel anxiety and stress, which can cause them to speed or swerve across the road.
产生路怒情绪的司机自身也会感到焦虑和紧张，进而可能出现超速行驶或突然变道等行为。
Experts like Leon James, a professor of traffic psychology at the University of Hawaii, US, warn that experiencing these moments, especially repeatedly, could be harmful to our health due to the number of stress hormones entering our bodies.
美国夏威夷大学交通心理学教授利昂·詹姆斯等专家提醒，这类情绪爆发的时刻，尤其是反复出现时，会使大量压力荷尔蒙进入人体，对健康造成损害。
So, what can cause us to experience road rage?
那么，哪些情况会引发路怒症呢？
Being tailgated, undertaken on a busy motorway, seeing someone swooping across several lanes, chatting on their phone, or hogging the middle lane in front of us are just some of the things that may stress us.
被后车跟车过近、在繁忙的高速公路上被从内侧车道超车、看到有人突然连续变道、开车时打电话，或是有人长时间霸占中间车道行驶，这些都可能让我们感到烦躁。
And what about parking?
停车时的情况呢？
Someone stealing the space we wanted at the last second could tip us over the edge!
就在你准备停车的最后一刻，有人抢了你的车位，这足以让你情绪失控！
Being aware of what can trigger these feelings of rage may be key to controlling it.
了解哪些因素会触发愤怒情绪，或许是控制路怒症的关键。
So what can we do to keep relaxed?
那么，我们该如何保持放松的心态呢？
Try driving in a good mood, and if you see a traffic jam, just remember that they can’t be avoided.
尽量带着好心情开车，如果遇到交通堵塞，要记住这是不可避免的情况。
And try leaving a little earlier in future.
以后可以试着早点出门。
Also, if you see someone who is really angry, try not to maintain eye contact, and don’t get out of the car to confront them.
此外，如果看到有人怒气冲冲，尽量不要和对方对视，也不要下车对峙。
And if you feel stressed and anxious, try pulling over somewhere and resting while you calm down.
如果你自己感到紧张焦虑，尝试把车停在安全的地方，休息一下，平复情绪。
So the next time you feel stressed while driving, just remember road rage can happen to anyone – and relaxing a bit when you feel that way may not just make it safer for you, but for others too.
所以下次开车感到压力时，请记住，任何人都可能患上路怒症。当你感到烦躁时，试着放松一点，这不仅能让你自己更安全，也能为他人带来安全。